<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>ODEKA A.S.B.L News</title>
<link>https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/</link>
<atom:link href="https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Latest updates and announcements from ODEKA A.S.B.L.</description>
<generator>quarto-1.4.551</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>James Robinson laureate of the 2024 Nobel Prize in Economics</title>
  <dc:creator>Adrien Foutelet</dc:creator>
  <link>https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/posts/news20241014.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 
<style>
/* Hide the visible description under the title block on THIS page */
header.quarto-title-block .description,
.quarto-title .description,
.quarto-title-meta .description,
p.description {
  display: none !important;
}
</style>
<p><a href="../../04_news/index.html" class="breadcrumb" style="font-size:0.9rem; text-transform:uppercase; letter-spacing:0.05em; color:#0077b5;">← Back to News</a></p>
<p><strong>We are proud to celebrate James A. Robinson, founding member of ODEKA A.S.B.L and Executive Board member, who has been awarded the 2024 Nobel Prize in Economic Sciences.</strong></p>
<p>James A. Robinson, a founding member of ODEKA A.S.B.L and professor at the University of Chicago’s Harris School of Public Policy, was awarded the Sveriges Riksbank Prize in Economic Sciences in Memory of Alfred Nobel. He shares the prize with Daron Acemoglu and Simon Johnson “for studies of how institutions are formed and affect prosperity.” Robinson’s work has profoundly reshaped our understanding of why some nations flourish while others remain trapped in poverty. Together with his co-laureates, he has shown how differences in political and economic institutions, many rooted in the legacies of European colonization, persist over time and continue to shape patterns of prosperity today. Their theoretical contributions have also deepened our understanding of how institutions evolve and how change becomes possible.</p>
<p>A central figure in the field of political economy and development, Robinson combines rigorous mathematical and quantitative analysis with deep historical research, case studies, and fieldwork. His research spans Latin America and sub-Saharan Africa, with extensive field experience in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Nigeria, Sierra Leone, Bolivia, and beyond. He is the co-author, with Acemoglu, of three landmark books (Economic Origins of Dictatorship and Democracy, Why Nations Fail, and The Narrow Corridor) that have shaped global debates on institutions, state formation, and development.</p>
<p>James Robinson’s connection to ODEKA A.S.B.L runs deep. In the early 2010s, he was part of the original team that traveled to Kasai, driven by his idea to study the political and historical legacy of the Kuba Kingdom after a formative conversation with a Congolese political leader. That journey laid the foundations for what would become the Kuba Kingdom project, a cornerstone of ODEKA A.S.B.L’s early research and one that continues to influence institutional economics today. ODEKA A.S.B.L is proud to have contributed to the research agenda that ultimately led to this Nobel Prize.</p>
<p>Beyond his towering scholarly influence, James Robinson is deeply admired by everyone at ODEKA A.S.B.L, especially by the younger researchers. He is renowned not only for his brilliance but also for his exceptional kindness, generosity, and humility. He speaks with every team member as if they were themselves Nobel laureates, asking thoughtful questions about their knowledge and ideas, and fostering a spirit of genuine intellectual curiosity and mutual respect.</p>
<p>We at ODEKA A.S.B.L are honored to count James Robinson among our founders and leaders. His Nobel Prize is not only a recognition of his extraordinary contributions to the field, but also a celebration of the collaborative spirit, curiosity, and humanity that have defined ODEKA’s work since its inception.</p>
<p>Congratulations, Jim, on this historic and deeply deserved recognition.</p>


 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/posts/news20241014.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/images/news20241014.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>New Kananga Team Takes Over Operations</title>
  <dc:creator>Adrien Foutelet</dc:creator>
  <link>https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/posts/news20220912.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 
<style>
/* Hide the visible description under the title block on THIS page */
header.quarto-title-block .description,
.quarto-title .description,
.quarto-title-meta .description,
p.description {
  display: none !important;
}
</style>
<p><a href="../../04_news/index.html" class="breadcrumb" style="font-size:0.9rem; text-transform:uppercase; letter-spacing:0.05em; color:#0077b5;">← Back to News</a></p>
<p><strong>The end of a six-week transition between the outgoing Country Director and the three new members of the Kananga team</strong></p>
<p>Robin Benabid Jegaden, the new Country Director, and Dylan Reich, the new Program Manager, arrived in Kananga in early August, where they joined Laure Lepine, the new Research Intern, who had arrived a few weeks earlier. The three will steer ODEKA A.S.B.L. through the months ahead.</p>
<p>Over six weeks, outgoing Country Director Adrien Foutelet introduced them to ODEKA A.S.B.L.’s employees, contractors, and partners, as well as key stakeholders in Kananga. They received extensive training on the organization’s management, current financial and HR priorities, and the scientific and practical dimensions of ODEKA A.S.B.L.’s main ongoing project, Religion &amp; Development.</p>
<p>While the baseline phase of this project is now fully complete, the team will oversee one ongoing wave of intervention and prepare to launch the final, tenth wave in the coming weeks. The intervention phase is projected to conclude in about seven months. They will also manage the shorter but crucial endline survey waves, five of which remain to be conducted.</p>
<p>As Religion &amp; Development enters its final stage, ODEKA A.S.B.L. is preparing to embark on a new horizon: Legal Antecedents of Fiscal Capacity, an ambitious project originally conceived by James Robinson. The three young researchers will play a key role as the practical hands in the field, devising concrete solutions and implementing actions in response to the principal investigators’ directives.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Adrien Foutelet will transition to a new role as Director of Finance &amp; Operations, joining Jonathan Weigel on the UC Berkeley campus to oversee project finances and serve as the day-to-day bridge between the field team and the principal investigators.</p>
<p>In the coming months, the Kananga team may welcome additional members, as the workload promises to grow significantly. Good luck to our three new recruits — and stay tuned!</p>


 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/posts/news20220912.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/images/news20220912.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Visit of James Robinson and Jon Weigel to the field</title>
  <dc:creator>Adrien Foutelet</dc:creator>
  <link>https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/posts/news20220718.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 
<style>
/* Hide the visible description under the title block on THIS page */
header.quarto-title-block .description,
.quarto-title .description,
.quarto-title-meta .description,
p.description {
  display: none !important;
}
</style>
<p><a href="../../04_news/index.html" class="breadcrumb" style="font-size:0.9rem; text-transform:uppercase; letter-spacing:0.05em; color:#0077b5;">← Back to News</a></p>
<p><strong>End of a productive two-week visit marks the beginning of a new multi-year project for ODEKA A.S.B.L.</strong></p>
<p>ODEKA A.S.B.L.’s team in Kananga had the privilege of welcoming and working with principal investigators James Robinson and Jon Weigel over the past two weeks. They were accompanied by Mats Ahrenshop, a PhD student from Oxford University, to prepare a new research project exploring how securing land property rights could foster tax compliance.</p>
<p>The visit included focus groups with customary chiefs, lawyers, and citizens, as well as meetings with key stakeholders such as Governor Jon Kabeya Shikayi, Secretary of Finance Jim Mukenge, and Chief Kalamaba, King of the Lulua Bashilange. The local team, Eva Davoine, Adrien Foutelet, and Morgane Garcia, worked closely with the principal investigators each day, contributing to the intervention design, the practical solutions envisioned, and the theoretical foundation of the forthcoming paper.</p>


 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/posts/news20220718.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://odeka-asbl.github.io/04_news/images/news20220718.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
